EFE BUYURAN

Sn. Front-End Developer



efebuyuran@gmail.com efebuyuran.com Istanbul/Turkey

Hello!

I'm a **Sn. Front-End Developer** from **Istanbul with 8 years of experience**, specializing in building modern user interfaces with **React & TypeScript** with a strong emphasis on pixel-perfect deliveries.

Having worked across products used by millions of people, I'm looking to use this experience to create new and exciting apps. I've worked for companies such as **Riot Games**, **Spinmatic Entertainment**, **Hyundai**, and **Huawei** in the past.

I believe in honesty, teamwork, and positivity for an efficient work environment. While being **open to feedback**, **accepting responsibility**, and **attention to detail** are my personal approach to professional work.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GrubTech - Software Engineer

Remote ~ Feb. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Created digital solutions with React & TypeScript for a cloud kitchen management services for restaurants.

Riot Games - Software Engineer

Istanbul ~ March 2019 - Jul. 2021

- Worked on integrating RTL support for League of Legends Client Application. Since this was new to Riot, our team took the initiative to lead RTL support for other Riot services including, Riot Client, Player support hub, and Login services using Javascript, Stylus, and RTLCSS plugin.
- Created scalable Single Page Applications to promote in-game store merchandise on League of Legends Client Hub using React, TypeScript and Styled Components.
- Integrated an independent streamer to lolesports.com with React.
- Rebranded LoL Cafe B2B web application (lolcafe.tr.leagueoflegends.com). I was merely responsible for Front-End development but ended up contributing to the design as well.
- Supervised development for User Generated Content competition app created with React.

Spinmatic Entertainment - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2019

- Worked on the development of a pre-designed mobile app that supports multiple slot games, took responsibility, and delivered a new UX-friendly design with better features using Adobe Tools, React and Redux and SASS.
- Setup a paytable app to work inside slot games which supported manual theming for different game designs, using native Javascript, SASS and HTML.

The King Content Creative Agency - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Apr. 2016 - Nov. 2017

- Created Single Page Applications for marketing promotions of Hyundai, Huawei, and Aygaz.
- Built websites for small businesses.
- Made animated banner ads with HTML5 & CSS.

N'oluyo - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Sep - Dec 2015

- Maintained an existing web platform, fixed bugs, provided UX solutions, implemented new features.

1V1Y - Jnr. Graphic Designer Istanbul ~ Feb - Jul 2015

- I was responsible from providing page designs for an online magazine that features fashion elements and inspirations.

FRONT-END SKILLS

HTML 5

CSS

- SASS
- Stylus
- Styled components

JavaScript

- ES6
- TypeScript
- React, Redux
- Restful APIs, GraphQL
- Mocha, Chai, Sinon

Build Automation

- NPM & NVM
- Gulp
- Webpack

Mobile Development

- Dart & Flutter

Other

- Lighthouse
- Cross-Browser & Platform Compatibility

UI & UX

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Figma
- Responsive Design
- CSS Animations
- Dynamic SVG
- RightToLeft Interfaces

EDUCATION

Istanbul Commerce University

Visual Communication

2009 - 2015

Yelkikanat And. Meslek Lisesi

Vocational High School, Computer 2004 - 2009

ISTEK Acıbadem College

Middle School 2000 - 2004

Eyüboğlu College

Primary Education

1995 - 2000

LANGUAGES

Turkish is my native language. I can read, write, and speak fluently in English.